Guide to the Ira S. Kaye Scrapbook MC.80
New York University Archives
Ira S. Kaye Scrapbook
1937-1987
1937-1941
New York University Archives
Kaye, Ira S.
MC.80
0.75 Linear Feet in one manuscript box and one half manuscript box
The Ira S. Kaye Scrapbook represents the personal scrapbook compiled by Ira S. Kaye during the years 1937-1941, when he was a student at the University Heights campus of New York University. The scrapbook contains ephemera such as ticket stubs, event programs, invitations and other school-related items.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions with the exception of individual student records in box 1 folders 3, 6, and 13, and box 2 folder 4 that are restricted in compliance with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA).
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Ira S. Kaye in May 1987; additional materials were donated in August 1987. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 87.022 and 87.030.
Appraisal
Thirteen photographs that were not pasted in the scrapbook were moved to Ira S. Kaye's portrait file.
Arrangement
Materials in the scrapbook have been divided into two volumes and a missing pages section. The pages were kept in their original order.
Biographical Note
Ira S. Kaye was born on March 21, 1921, in New York City. He was a 1941 graduate of New York University and was a student at the University Heights campus from 1937-1941. Kaye was enrolled in the College of Arts and Pure Science and graduated with a Bachelor of Science degree in accounting. While at NYU he was the feature editor of the student newspaper, the Heights Daily News. Many of the clippings in this scrapbook are articles that he wrote while working at the Heights Daily News. He was also the editor-in-chief of the Heights' 1941 Violet, the campus yearbook, and associate editor of the 1940 Violet. Kaye was involved in Quaigh and the Rifle and Pistol Club and was a member of several committees, including the Lawrence House Committee, the Freshman Camp Executive Staff, the Ducking Committee, the Fordham Rally Committee, the Mall Committee, and the Senior Ball and Junior Prom Committees. In addition to these, he was also a member of Perstare et Praestare, the Gilbert and Sullivan Society and the Hamilton Commerce Society. As a graduate of the R.O.T.C. program at NYU, Kaye was enlisted as a Lieutenant in the U.S. Army and was stationed in Camp Edwards, Massachusetts, in 1942. In 1952, Kaye was elected second vice president for the South Florida chapter of the Alumni Association. In 1953, Kaye was promoted to assistant comptroller of the National Silver Company.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to the fragile nature of the original materials, researchers must use the access copies located in boxes 1 and 2.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of one scrapbook from the years 1931-1941. Most of the clippings found in the scrapbook include sporting event tickets, programs, exam papers and invitations to various NYU events. Many of the clippings are annotated by Kaye, giving insight to all the activities that he was involved with. Miscellaneous pages were also included in the collection. These pages were once a part of the original scrapbook but had been misplaced. They were sent to the Archives shortly after Kaye discovered that they were missing. The collection also includes additional items that Kaye sent over, such as Alumni Bulletins about himself and other post-graduate events that he attended.
Clippings (information artifacts); College sports.; College student newspapers and periodicals.; Scrapbooks.; New York University. University Heights; New York University -- Students
- Accession information, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Copied Volume I of Ira S. Kaye's Scrapbook pg. 1-84, 1937-1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Original Items: Volume I of Ira S. Kaye's Scrapbook pg 1-84 (1 of 2), 1937-1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Original Items: Volume 1 of Ira S. Kaye's Scrapbook (2 of 2), 1937-1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Copied Volume II of Ira S. Kaye's Scrapbook pg. 85-142, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Original items: Volume II of Ira S. Kaye's Scrapbook pg. 85-142 (1 of 2), 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Original Items: Volume II of Ira S. Kaye's Scrapbook pg. 85-142 (2 of 2), 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Copied Miscellaneous Pages of Ira S. Kaye's Scrapbook, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Original Items of Miscellaneous Pages of Ira S. Kaye's Scrapbook, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Tie from Original Miscellaneous Pages of Ira S. Kaye's Scrapbook, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Letter Regarding Additional Material, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Additional Items from Ira S. Kaye's Scrapbook, 1939-1941 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Copies of Missing Pages from Ira S. Kaye's Scrapbook, 1938-1953 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Original Items: Missing Pages of Ira S. Kaye's Scrapbook (1 of 2), 1938-1940 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Original Items: Missing Pages of Ira S. Kaye's Scrapbook (2 of 2), 1940-1953 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Additional Original Items from Ira S. Kaye's Scrapbook: Alumni, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Additional Original Items from Ira S. Kaye's Scrapbook: Perstare Et Praestare, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Ira S. Kaye's Scrapbook Collection: Record of Receipts & Disbursements, 1937-1941 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Ira. S. Kaye's Scrapbook Collection: Notebook: Volume II Theory of Accounts, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Ira S. Kaye's Scrapbook Collection: Miscellaneous, 1939-1965 (Box 2, Folder 11)